Experienced solution-driven *Full Stack Developer* contributing to highly collaborative work environment, finding solutions and committing to highest standards of development with over 8 years experience.

4 years of proven freelance experience developing various consumer-focused and in-house websites spanning across multiple industries using various languages and frameworks for clients and companies from all over the world.

Location: Dandong, Liaoning, China **Email:** willierivera0815@gmail.com

Phone: +8613372983449

Github: https://github.com/WillieRivera **Portfolio:** https://yingxiongwen.netlify.com

MAIN SKILLS

FRONT END

- HTML5, Forms & Validations, SEO
- CSS3, Flex & Grid, Sass, PostCSS
- Tailwind CSS, Bootstrap, GSAP, Styled Components
- Typescript, ES6+, Vanilla JS
- React (Next, Gatsby, Hooks), Redux
- Angular, Vuex
- Semantic UI, Material UI, Ant Design
- JSON, AJAX, REST APIs, Angular

DEVOPS & MISC

- Git, Github, Bitbucket, CI/CD
- Azure, AWS Lambda, Heroku, Netlify
- Docker, Kubernetes
- Testing (Unit, E2E, Functional, etc)
- Cypress, JEST

BACK END

- Node, Express, Nest, Strapi
- Django, Python, PHP
- Web scraping
- MongoDB, PostgreSQL, Azure, Firebase
- Authentication (OAuth, JWT)
- Microservice, GraphQL, Apollo
- NATS, Stripe, TypeORM

SOFT & PERSONAL FAVORITE

- Creativity
- Problem Solving
- Teamwork
- Leadership
- · Attention to Detail
- Time Management
- Reading, Listening Music, Football

EXPERIENCES

Full Stack Developer

2017 - Present

Freelance

Dandong, Liaoning, China

- Development and delivery of consumer-faced and in-house projects to high quality standards.
- Worked in Agile-driven environment to effectively maintain project timelines and utilize available resources
- Testing and optimization for existing applications and refactoring existing code.

Full Stack Engineer

07/2021 - 11/2021

Сору

Philadelphia, United States

- Worked on Figma plugin frontend and FastAPI backend to convert figma code to react
- Integrated with Figma Developer API
- Suggested directions to improve usability of product by the use of SCSS
- Optimized style generation algorithm and approaches

Senior Web Engineer

01/2020 - 06/2021

Scalio

San Francisco, United States

- · Worked on Intuitive Supr project that is used as an in-house education platform for surgeons
- Set up frontend architecture and chose the technology stack
- Supported for the project with a continuous cycle of changes and additions of new feature
- Participated in meeting with clients to discuss about the scope and requirements of project
- Provided feedback to client's design team in relation to in-progress UI mock-ups for future features

Senior Software Engineer

11/2018 - 10/2019

Silicon Jungles

Singapore

- Worked on various consumer-faced products meeting high requirements and standards
- Participated in cross-functional team discussions to formulate effective development and maintenance strategies
- Provided direction for improvement and significantly improved the loading speed of tables on Sheet project

Web Developer

04/2018 - 11/2018

AIR Concepts

Hong Kong

- Worked closely with software development and testing team members to design and develop robust solutions to meet platform requirements for functionality, scalability and performance.
- Rapidly prototyped new data processing capabilities to confirm integration feasibility into existing systems.

Senior Web Developer

05/2014 - 10/2017

Neusoft

Shenyang, Liaoning, China

- Solved problems from existing websites and implemented enhancements that significantly improved web functionality and speed.
- Integrating and creating API endpoints.
- Developed and managed 10+ modern websites by using React, Angular and GSAP Animation.
- Mentored and oversaw 8 new team members and junior developers, instructing them on the company policies, day-to-day working, best practices and modern technologies.

Software Engineer

11/2012 – 01/2014

Tencent

Shenyang, Liaoning, China

- Resolved & debugged technical issues related to Super App.
- Improving the quality of mobile Super App in terms of rendering and resource usage.

EDUCATION

Shanghai Jiaotong University

Bachelor of Computer Science

09/2007 – 07/2011 Shanghai, China

PROJECTS

Supr, United States - Medical platform for surgeons

Supr is an in-house website where surgeons can register, upload, view their surgery videos and compare it those from experts, learn from visualized table, scatter-plot metrics.

- Frontend with Angular, backend with Nestjs
- Video stream with Brightcove
- Typeorm, Postgres, Redis for database operation
- AWS to GCP migration for uploaded videos
- Visualization with Apexcharts
- Ng-zorro as base library, ng-xs for state management
- Nx monorepo structure

Sheet, United States - Online multi-user sheet editor

Sheet is a sheet editor which is quite similar to google-sheet, but with less and unique features, it was designed to support multi-user edit and creation of relationship between tables.

- Frontend with Next, backend with strapi CMS
- Support for different cell types including files, Froala-editor content, Icons
- Real-time edit with Pusher and Redis
- Customization of Handsontable

Artition, Hong Kong - Auction platform for art products

Artition is an auction platform where users can view the art products from artists, bid on it and share information about them with others.

- Microservice architecture with services deployed to AWS using Serverless framework
- Apollo GraphQL, integration of graphs using Apollo Federation, Apollo react hooks, Hasura
- Postgres and Typeorm for database operation
- App development using React Native, admin dashboard with Ant Design
- Cronjob to run checks for database update
- Elasticsearch for search speed optimization
- Backend development with Nestjs, front-end with React
- NATS for communication between microservices

Corpsec, Singapore - Online event organizing platform

Corpsec is a platform where coporation secretaries can register the events, activities, annual meetings and organize it.

- Backend with Django, frontend with Nextjs
- Online signing of documents with Eversign
- Mailing service with Sendgrid
- Visualization with Holistics and Highchart
- Database query edtior with pREST

Copy, United States - Figma plugin that converts figma design to React code

Copy is a Figma plugin that converts the figma design to productive React code.

- Backend with FastAPI, frontend with Vue
- Integration with Figma Developer API
- Express microservices to parse and format SCSS, React code
- Google OCR and machine learning algorithm to optimize the layout

House Pro Digital, Australia - A market-place for off-market property

House Pro Digital is a platform to sell and buy off-market property

- Front-end with Vue.js, Vuetify and Vuex
- Back-end using Node, Express
- Database using MongoDB

LANGUAGES

- Chinese Native
- English Fluent
- Japanese Beginner